RG 004:008, Bethany Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Bethany Probate Court records
1833-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Bethany District)
20.50 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1854-1958; Probate files, 1833-1976.
RG004_008
1911-001, 2011-064, and 2011-065
Historical Note
Bethany, New Haven County, Town established in May 1832, Parent Town: Woodbridge
The Bethany Probate District was constituted July 4, 1854, from the New Haven Probate District. On January 5, 2011 the Bethany Probate District merged with the Hamden Probate District to create the Hamden - Bethany Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethany and Hamden.
Town of Bethany, Probate District chronology:
May 1832 - July 3, 1854, New Haven District
July 4, 1854 - January 4, 2011, Bethany District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Hamden - Bethany District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-10, 1854-1958. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 10.
Probate files, 1833-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. Includes a small number of files from the New Haven Probate District that pre-date the creation of the Bethany Probate District in 1854. Most of these files are for incompetency cases.
Inventory control book, 1833-1950 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 10, including a 1A. The volume of bonds is unnumbered.
Probate files are arranged by accession. Each accession is arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in accession 1911-001 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-065.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - Bethany
Places:
Bethany (Conn.)
Alternate Creator:
Connecticut. Probate Court (New Haven District)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-064, Record books, 1854-1958; and Accession 2011-065, Probate files, 1884-1887, 1926-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 2-4, 6,8, 1855-1915; probate files 1833-1915 (Accession 1911-001 only); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-001 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 9, 1911 (1833-1920); November 3, 1921 (1837-1920); March 15, 1930 (1902-1928); March 27, 1936 (1903-1935); April 25, 1951 (1925-1950). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-064 and the probate files in accession 2011-065 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 9, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1854-1958; 6 cubic feet (12 volumes); 2011-064
  - Decrees, 1854-1876, 1894 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1855-1865 (Volume 1A)
    Contains guardians and conservators
  - Records, 1855-1876 (Volumne 2)
  - Wills & distributions, 1856-1906 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1865-1919 (Volume 4)
  - Decrees, 1876-1930 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1876-1889 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1883-1947 (Volume 7)
    Contains: 1) Election of judge of probate and town clerk; 2) Commitments
  - Records, 1889-1915 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1915-1932 (Volume 9)
  - Decrees, 1930-1958 (Volume 10)
  - Bonds, 1881-1915 (Volume Unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1833-1950; 4.50 cubic feet; 1911-001
  - Adams - Beecher, E. (Drawer 1)
  - Beecher, F. - Burns (Drawer 2)
  - Camp - Davidson (Drawer 3)
  - Davis - Durvey (Drawer 4)
  - Farrell - Headley (Drawer 5)
  - Holbeck - Johnson, F. (Drawer 6)
  - Johnson, J. - Lounsbury (Drawer 7)
  - MacClure - Peck, J. (Drawer 8)
  - Peck, L. - Ruttinger (Drawer 9)
  - Sackett - Sperry, E. (Drawer 10)
  - Sperry, G. - Todd (Drawer 11)
  - Tolles - Warner (Drawer 12)
  - Warriss - Wilcoxson (Drawer 13)
  - Wolter - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 14)
- Inventory Control Book, 1833-1950; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1911-002
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1884-1887,1926-1976; 10 cubic feet; 2011-065
  - Abromowitz - Clark, Noyes D. (Box 1)
  - Clark, Noyes D. - Downs (Box 2)
  - Durley - Heeran (Box 3)
  - Hein - Jennings (Box 4)
  - Johnson - Loeb (Box 5)
  - Loomis - Musto (Box 6)
  - Nettleton - Satow (Box 7)
  - Saxton - Thomas (Box 8)
  - Ticknell - Wooster (Box 9)
  - Worthington - Zwick (Box 10)